Guide to the Candida Scott Piel Papers and AmFAR Collection 1969-2003 (Bulk 1981-2003) MSS 142
Fales Library and Special Collections
Candida Scott Piel Papers and AmFAR Collection
Bulk, 1981-2003
1969-2003
MSS 142
Fales Library and Special Collections
4.25 linear feet (2 document cases, 2 flat boxes, 1 objects box)
The Candida Scott Piel Papers and AmFAR Collection contains administrative files, clippings, and ephemera related to Candida Scott Piel and her involvement with the Foundation for AIDS Research (AmFAR).
Piel, Candida Scott
Scope and Content
The Candida Scott Piel Papers and AmFAR Collection contains administrative files, clippings, and ephemera related to Candida Scott Piel's involvement with the Foundation for AIDS Research (AmFAR) and other AIDS and LGBT outreach initiatives. The materials have been arranged into three series:
Series I: Event Materials contains items related to specific events which Candida Scott Piel attended, or with which she was involved, including film festivals, LGBT rights events, and political meetings.
Series II: Subject Files contains clippings and research files unrelated to specific events.
Series III: Ephemera contains primarily promotional items such as buttons and t-shirts, related to groups or events.
Provenance
The Candida Scott Piel Papers and AmFAR Collection were acquired by donation in 2003 and 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Related Archival Materials note
Peter Lewis Allen Collection of Safe Sex Pamphlets
Biographical/Historical note
Candida Scott Piel worked with the Foundation for AIDS Research (AmFAR) and other Gay and Lesbian Advocates' Groups throughout the 1980s and 1990s. Her work included involvement with numerous outreach events, such as the annual New York City Gay Pride Celebration.
Arrangement
Materials have been processed at the folder level. Folders are arranged chronologically within each series.
AmFAR.; Administrative records.; AIDS (Disease); AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Gay activists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Minutes.; Pamphlets.; Safe sex in AIDS prevention |v Handbooks, manuals, etc.
- Series I: Event Materials
  - GMHC Morning Party, Aug 22, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Climax, Jun 26, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mr. Northeast Drummer Contest '94, Jul 31, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Relentless IV, Jan 15, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Equinox, Mar 19, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mr. Leather New York '95 [oversize], Apr 1, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mother's March Against AIDS, May 7, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Climax 1995, Jun 25, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Climax 1995 poster [oversize], Jun 25, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mr. Northeast Drummer '95, Jul 23, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Leather Party '95 in Hamburg, Aug 10, 1995-Aug 13, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Q&A with Dr. Mathilde Krim, Aug 12, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - GMHC Morning Party, Aug 20, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Saint at Large Black Party, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Afterglow, Jan 13, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - White Out, Feb 18, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mr. Leather New York '96 [oversize], Apr 27, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Northeast Mr. Drummer '96, Jun 23, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Climax '96, Jun 30, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Climax '96 posters [oversize], Jun 30, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Spirit, Oct 12, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Tribal, Nov 16, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Saint at Large Black Party, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Afterglow: The Beauty of Orion, Jan 18, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Afterglow: The Beauty of Orion poster [oversize], Jan 18, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Night of a Thousand Gowns, Mar 22, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Wicked, Apr 27, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Climax '97, Jun 29, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Climax '97 poster [oversize], Jun 29, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Steel Party, Pittsburgh, Sep 12, 1997-Sep 14, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 20 Red, Sep 20, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Dance of the Different Drummer, Sep 28, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Dance of the Different Drummer [oversize], Sep 28, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Saint at Large Black Party, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Afterglow: Ascension, Jan 17, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Equinox, Mar 22, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Sea Tea, May 31, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Climax '98, Jun 28, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Climax '98 poster [oversize], Jun 28, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - erie party '98, Jul 18, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Joey D, Birthday Party, Oct 28, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Home for the Holidays, Dec 5, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Saint at Large Black Party, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Alchemy, Jan 17, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Equinox, Mar 21, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Climax '99, Jun 27, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - erie party '99, Jul 17, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - The Druid's Dance, Oct 31, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Saint at Large Black Party, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Alchemy II, Jan 16, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Equinox, Mar 26, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Shoulder to Shoulder/Heart to Heart, Apr 30, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Tribe, Jun 25, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - erie party, Jul 15, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Saint at Large Black Party, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Alchemy III, Jan 14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Equinox, Mar 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Tribe, Jun 23, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Alchemy 4, Jan 20, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Tribe, Jun 29, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Trance/Dance, Jan 19, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - AIDS Walk, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Series II: Subject Files
  - Amfar Gay Outreach, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Fan Dancing, undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Yale and the Movement for Lesbian and Gay Rights, May 19, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Series III: Ephemera
  - Gay Pride March, CSLDC Marshall t-shirt, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Gay Pride March, CSLDC Marshall t-shirt, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Gay Pride March, CSLDC Marshall t-shirt, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Fairpac t-shirt, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Climb for the Cure t-shirt, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Big Guns baseball cap, 1994 (Box 2)
  - If Your Kids Had AIDS t-shirt, 1996 (Box 2)
  - If Your Mom Had AIDS t-shirt, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Climax t-shirt, Jun 27, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Alchemy II tank top, Jan 16, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Tribe tank top, Jun 25, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Avid Productions New Years Eve t-shirt, Dec 31, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Alchemy III tank top, Jan 14, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Tribe tank top, Jun 23, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Alchemy 4 tank top, Jan 20, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Tribe t-shirt, Jun 29, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Trance\Dance t-shirt, Jan 19, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Cosme's Coney Island Run t-shirt, undated (Box 2)
  - Silencio=Muerte t-shirt, undated (Box 2)
  - Twilo/Amfar t-shirts (2), undated (Box 2)
  - Buttons (13), undated (Box 3)
- Accretion 2007 - Series I: Event Materials
  - October 14th Film Project, circa 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gay Pride Festival Survey, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Badges, Membership Cards, 1984-2000, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Prejudice & Pride: The New York City Lesbian and Gay Community, World War II - Present", Tweed Gallery at City Hall Park, June 1-30 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - FAIRPAC Board Meeting, January 15 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Lesbian and Gay Agenda for the Nineties, February 14 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The International Festival of Lesbian and Gay Film, June 4-14 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New York City Lesbian and Gay Pride Celebration Pass, June 29 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Accretion 2007 - Series II: Subject Files
  - The Male Figure Review, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Deborah Glick Lesbian and Gay Community Endorsement List, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Inevitable Love: A Healthy Sex Video", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tales of the Closet..., 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Budget Planning, circa 1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Crissy" Pamphlet - Stop AIDS Project, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Sticker and Postcard, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Accretion 2007 - Series III: Ephemera
  - Buttons (7), 1987-91, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Gay Synagogue, Passover 1981 Yarmulke (Box 5, Object ID: 142.2.0001)
  - Award from the Greater Gotham Business Council, Inc. "in recognition of outstanding contributions to the New York City Lesbian and Gay Community", June 1985 (Box 5, Object ID: 142.2.0002)
  - "Tribe" Cotton T-shirt, 2002 (Box 5, Object ID: 142.2.0003)
  - "'Be Fabulous!' Razor Sharp" Cotton T-shirt, undated
  - "Pride" Cotton Tank Top, undated (Box 5, Object ID: 142.2.0005)